[
  {
    "question": "Whose series of photographs showed the effects of mercury pollution on a Japanese community?",
    "a": "W. Eugene Smith",
    "b": "Alma Thomas",
    "c": "Chris Jordan",
    "d": "Mel Chin",
    "e": "Edward S. Curtis",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following descriptions BEST matches Yoa Lu’s New Landscapes?",
    "a": "pictures of urban scenes transformed into serene nature settings",
    "b": "digital collages of plastic waste arranged to form designs",
    "c": "colorful pictures of rivers polluted by industrial mining",
    "d": "images of garbage resembling nature scenes from scroll paintings",
    "e": "photographs showing the gradual decline of forests across America",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Edward Burtynsky is MOST associated with the term",
    "a": "landscape portraits",
    "b": "abstracted pollution",
    "c": "environmental realism",
    "d": "toxic sublime",
    "e": "photographic Impressionism",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Agnes Denes began her career as a(n)",
    "a": "professor",
    "b": "poet",
    "c": "filmmaker",
    "d": "sculptor",
    "e": "environmental lawyer",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The chain-wrapped trees in Agnes Denes’s second iteration of Rice/Tree/Burial are a symbol of",
    "a": "the interdependence between humans and the environment",
    "b": "humanity’s exploitation of the natural world",
    "c": "the historical significance of nature",
    "d": "the resilience of nature in urban environments",
    "e": "the damaging effects of climate change on forests",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term “Eco-logic” refers to",
    "a": "land-art pieces that transform the surrounding environment",
    "b": "large-scale works that incorporate innovations from nature",
    "c": "performance pieces that educate viewers on thinking sustainably",
    "d": "digital works that examine organisms and their environments",
    "e": "site-oriented works that are conscious of environmental concerns",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company dumped thousands of tons of toxins into Love Canal?",
    "a": "Hooker Chemical Company",
    "b": "Sumitomo Chemical America",
    "c": "Glencore Mining Company",
    "d": "Newmont Mining Corporation",
    "e": "Core Petroleum Company",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following aspects of Agnes Denes’s second iteration of Rice/Tree/Burial also appeared in her first?",
    "a": "chained trees",
    "b": "mutated rice",
    "c": "a plaque",
    "d": "a documentary film",
    "e": "a buried time capsule",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "The land used in Wheatfield had previously been a part of the",
    "a": "Lenox Library",
    "b": "Battery Park Landfill",
    "c": "Pennsylvania Station",
    "d": "Olin Chemical Plant",
    "e": "Trinity Church",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The harvested grain from Wheatfield toured the globe as part of an exhibition aimed at",
    "a": "promoting sustainability",
    "b": "reducing global warming",
    "c": "ending world hunger",
    "d": "expanding rural farmland",
    "e": "eliminating GMO ingredients",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following photographs is NOT one of the nine commonly circulated images of Wheatfield?",
    "a": "an aerial shot of the rectangular plot of land",
    "b": "the wheat being harvested",
    "c": "Denes planting a small seedling",
    "d": "the barren land before planting began",
    "e": "Denes walking through the field",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Wheatfield juxtaposes ideas of",
    "a": "technology and nature",
    "b": "urban and rural life",
    "c": "wealth and poverty",
    "d": "past and future",
    "e": "design and sustainability",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Wheatfield was located closest to the",
    "a": "Love Canal",
    "b": "AT&T Building",
    "c": "World Trade Center",
    "d": "Chrysler Building",
    "e": "Empire State Building",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following governments sponsored Denes’s Tree Mountain?",
    "a": "Sweden",
    "b": "France",
    "c": "England",
    "d": "Finland",
    "e": "Spain",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Attached to Denes’s Tree Mountain is a proviso stating that",
    "a": "the site will be open to the public year-round",
    "b": "every tree must be planted next to a time capsule",
    "c": "future seeds will be transported around the world",
    "d": "each volunteer will hold the rights to the tree they planted for 400 years",
    "e": "the trees will be harvested in 100 years",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what state did Noah Purifoy begin his art career?",
    "a": "California",
    "b": "Oregon",
    "c": "Alaska",
    "d": "Alabama",
    "e": "Georgia",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Noah Purifoy started his art career by making",
    "a": "handcrafts",
    "b": "design objects",
    "c": "informal caricatures",
    "d": "portrait paintings",
    "e": "block-printed textiles",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1964, Noah Purifoy co-founded an arts center named after a(n)",
    "a": "Southern California university",
    "b": "West Coast Native American tribe",
    "c": "artwork in Los Angeles",
    "d": "famous California building",
    "e": "small beach town",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What event directly inspired the creation of 66 Signs of Neon?",
    "a": "the 9/11 terrorist attacks",
    "b": "the opening of the Hollywood Walk of Fame",
    "c": "the Santa Barbara oil spill",
    "d": "the Watts Rebellion",
    "e": "the assassination of John F. Kennedy",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "With whom did Noah Purifoy work to create 66 Signs of Neon?",
    "a": "Bernadette Demientieff",
    "b": "W. Eugene Smith",
    "c": "Vladimir Tatlin",
    "d": "Subhankar Banerjee",
    "e": "Judson Powell",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "66 Signs of Neon PRIMARILY sent a message about",
    "a": "gender inequality",
    "b": "negative externalities",
    "c": "racial discrimination",
    "d": "government corruption",
    "e": "mass media",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the late 1970s, Noah Purifoy transitioned from a career as an artist to one in",
    "a": "community volunteering",
    "b": "higher education",
    "c": "climate activism",
    "d": "professional writing",
    "e": "arts administration",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "To what town did Noah Purifoy move in order to create outdoor artwork?",
    "a": "Avalon",
    "b": "Joshua Tree",
    "c": "Napa Valley",
    "d": "La Jolla",
    "e": "Watts",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What best describes the Noah Purifoy Outdoor Desert Art Museum?",
    "a": "several pieces displayed to showcase the impact of the Watts Rebellion",
    "b": "site-specific sculptures around Noah Purifoy’s home",
    "c": "a collection of artworks used to advocate for environmental conservation",
    "d": "a museum established to display art from historically overlooked artists",
    "e": "a multimedia effort to show the effects of oil drilling and fracking through art",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did junk art appeal to Noah Purifoy?",
    "a": "It created beautiful art with materials which would otherwise pollute the Earth.",
    "b": "Creating valuable art from 'worthless' junk gave a sense of satisfaction.",
    "c": "Junk was often created out of consumerist packages that were intended to be artistic.",
    "d": "Junk reflected the material condition of America and thus felt more personal.",
    "e": "Junk was often disposed of in communities of color, and thus became accessible.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Offshore Drilling invokes the architecture of",
    "a": "Harry Drinkwater",
    "b": "Frank Gehry",
    "c": "Judson Powell",
    "d": "Isak Autrey",
    "e": "Anthony Caro",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Offshore Drilling tackles all of the following subjects EXCEPT",
    "a": "the greenhouse effect",
    "b": "oil extraction",
    "c": "environmental racism",
    "d": "toxicity",
    "e": "poverty",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does oil drilling cause unequal harm?",
    "a": "Pollution from drilling tends to affect poorer communities.",
    "b": "Oil rigs disrupt the agricultural lifestyle of communities.",
    "c": "Establishing an oil rig removes jobs from poorer communities.",
    "d": "Oil subsidies remove the aid available to poorer communities.",
    "e": "Starting an oil rig displaces the poorer communities.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following artworks is NOT in the Noah Purifoy Outdoor Desert Art Museum?",
    "a": "Offshore Drilling",
    "b": "Carousel",
    "c": "66 Signs of Neon",
    "d": "Ode to Frank Gehry",
    "e": "Bowling Balls I",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following museums did Frank Gehry design?",
    "a": "the Guggenheim Museum",
    "b": "the Smithsonian National Museum of Natural History",
    "c": "the Metropolitan Museum of Modern Art in New York",
    "d": "the Minnesota Museum of Art",
    "e": "the Louvre",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  }
]